(忆往昔)
迪恩
Hey, Dean.
是我
It's me.
-你回来多久了  萨姆  -一年了
- How long you been back, Sam? - About a year.
这一年来你一直都在这世上
You been back practically this whole time?!
你终于得偿所愿了
You finally had what you wanted.
我要的是我弟弟  活着
I wanted my brother, alive.
你渴望的是家庭
You wanted a family.
只是由于我们的生存方式  你才不得不放弃
You only gave it up because of the way we lived.
但你已拥有了常人的生活  建立了家庭
But you had something, and you were building something.
你已经金盆洗手了  迪恩
You got out, Dean!
你已摆脱了这种生活
You walked away from the life.
那种幸福
And it's as close to happiness
是猎魔人永远不能享有的
As I've ever seen a hunter get.
我跟其他人一起干
I hooked up with some other people.
-你竟跟陌生人共事  -他们算得上家人
- You? Working with strangers? - They're more like family.
格温·坎贝尔  那是克里斯蒂安和马克
Gwen Campbell. That's Christian and Mark.
坎贝尔  就跟
Campbell? Like...
跟你妈妈一个姓
Like your mom.
我是你外公
I'm your grandfather.
萨穆埃尔  不可能
Samuel? You can't be
我们觉得是救了萨姆的东西将我复活的
We're guessing whatever pulled sam up pulled me down.
-但你们还不知道它是什么  -没错
- But you don't know what that is. - Bingo.
变形怪  能将自己伪装成任何人
Shapeshifter? Something that can make itself look like anyone?
传说这种生物能衍变成
Legends of creatures who can transform themselves
任何动物或人类
into animals or other men.
当他们变形时  可能会蜕皮
When the shapeshifter changes shape, maybe it sheds.
跟一起我走吗
You coming with me?
不  我要回去陪着莉莎和本
No, I'm going back for Lisa and Ben.
你会让他们陷入险境的
You'll be putting them in danger.
那该怎样  难道撇下他们  无人保护
So, what, it's better to leave them alone, unprotected,
这样他们就不危险了吗
And then they're not in danger?
是我走入了他们的生活  才使他们身陷险境
I made them vulnerable the moment I knocked on their door.
常打给我  听到没
Keep in touch, you hear?
必须的
Of course.
(如今)
不
No!
乖  没事的
It's okay.
(厨具: 平底锅  烤箱  菜板)
怎么啦
What's up?
没啥
Nothing.
起码先好好看看这地方
At least wait till you've checked the place out
再讨厌也不迟吧
Before you hate it.
敞开心扉  我只求你做到这一点
Open mind. That's all I ask.
好吧  好吧
Yeah, all right.
我一会儿回来
I'll be back.
哇哦  嘿  急啥呀
Whoa, hey, where's the fire?
我想去看看这个街区
I'm just going to check out the block.
留下你妈妈自己收拾厨房吗  过来帮忙
And let your mom unpack the kitchen by herself? Come on.
我们等会出去吃午饭  再去会会邻居  行吗
We'll go for lunch later, scope out the neighborhood. Right?
好  这主意不错
Yeah, sounds like a plan.
过来  帮我一把
Come on, why don't you give me a hand?
(兰辛市  密歇根州)
在哪儿找到尸体的
Where'd you find the bodies?
在楼上发现了父母的尸体
We found the parents upstairs.
相当残忍
Pretty brutal.
是非法闯入吗
Break-in?
警铃一直没响过
Eh, alarm never went off.
有这孩子的线索吗
Any leads on the baby?
-还没有  -你怎么看
- None yet. - So what do you think?
你觉得她安全吗  还活着吗
You think it's okay? Alive?
现在我不抱希望了
I did yesterday.
谢谢你
Thank you.
-你好  -嘿
- Hi. - Hey.
一个起司披萨  一个什锦披萨
Uh, one cheese, one everything?
没错
Yeah.
谢谢了
Thank you.
钱给你  不用找了
There you go. Keep the change.
-谢谢  -谢谢你
- Thanks. - Thanks.
怎么啦
What?
我还以为要出去吃
I thought we were going out.
哦  对啊  我忘了  抱歉
Oh, yeah, I forgot. I'm sorry.
看出来了
Sure.
我去找盘子
I'll look for plates.
喂  我四处检查过了
Hey. So, I've been all over this --
没硫磺  没电磁反应
No sulfur, no EMF.
我觉得可能没我们的事
Starting to think maybe it's not our kind of thing.
四对被屠杀的夫妇  都在同一个州同一个区
Four couples slaughtered, one part of the state,
而且是接二连三地发生
Within days of each other.
房子都是反锁的  可四个婴儿都被带走了
That's four babies taken from locked houses.
该死的
Damn it!
跟我说说普通人如何能办到
Explain to me how any version of that is natural.
对  我同意  现场非常恐怖
No, no, I agree. It's awful.
我只是说  这事儿也许该由警方介入
I'm just saying, this one might be on the police.
总之  我们要找的
Okay, so, either we got monsters
要么是些抓婴儿吃的怪物
grabbing babies to make baby stew,
要么就是一群
or we got a bunch of psychotic yokels
抓婴儿吃的神经病
grabbing babies to make baby stew.
不管怎样孩子都会被吃  这可不妙
Either way, it's baby stew, which is bad.
你是不耐烦了吗  有急事吗
So-- am I boring you? You got someplace you need to be?
-没  没  我懂了  -很好
- No, no, no. I get it. - Good.
有时候我还真搞不懂你  萨姆
Sometimes I wonder about you, Sam.
有时候我自己也搞不懂自己
Sometimes I wonder about me, too.
好了  我再把资料重新看看
Well, I will go back over everything,
看我们有没有漏掉什么
See if there's anything we missed.
对了  探员说房子里的警铃一直没响过
Hey, detective said the alarm in the house never went off.
能不能快速查下
You mind taking a quick look,
另几家的警报系统是不是哈珀凯恩保安公司的
see if anybody else had a system from Harper Caine Security?
好  没问题
Yeah, sure.
我正在努力玩儿转电脑
Any chance I get to hop on a computer.
你搞什么
What the hell?
给我
Hey, hey, give me that!
-你乱动什么  -我只是想瞧瞧
- What do you think you're doing? - I just wanted to see it.
给我听好
Listen to me --
永远不许再打开这个箱子
Don't ever open this trunk.
听懂没
You understand me?
好的  抱歉
Okay. Sorry.
可我不明白
But I don't get it.
你像我这么大的时候  都有自己的来复枪了
You had your own rifle when you were my age.
本  记住我的话
Ben, mark my words --
永远别和枪打交道  永远
You will never, ever shoot a gun. Ever.
我知道怎么回事
I know what's going on.
你觉得会有东西来找我们的麻烦
You think something might be coming for us.
没那回事儿
There's nothing coming for us.
你能做的我也能做  你可以教我怎么用枪
I could do what you do! You could teach me how to shoot --
不准再提枪  听到没
Shut up about the freakin' gun, okay?!
好的
Okay.
对不起
Sorry.
I'm sorry.
你猜对了
You were right.
所有被害家庭都用的那家公司的报警系统
Every family that got hit -- Harper Caine Security.
我调查了客户记录
So I pulled the client records.
好  看看还有没有情况类似的家庭
Right, to see if there's any other families who fit the profile.
还有一对幸福的夫妇
And there is another happy couple, walking and talking.
六个月大的孩子
6-month old baby --
和其他家庭一样
like all the others.
地址告诉我
What's the address?
怎么回事
What happened?
本把自己锁在房间里几个小时了
Ben's been locked in his room for hours.
他说你吼他
Says you yelled at him.
他做了什么
what did he do?
没什么
Nothing.
那你做了什么
What did you do?
他动了我的工具箱  我不该发火的
He got into my tools. I shouldn't have got mad.
想聊聊吗
You want to talk about this?
聊什么
About?
冲本大吼  把我们关在这房子里
Yelling at Ben, keeping us in the house.
我在保证我们的安全
I'm trying to keep us safe here.
我不是来吵架的好吧
I'm not arguing, okay?
你是内行  我只是问问
You're the expert. I'm just asking.
你说你和弟弟已经
You said that you and your brother
解决了那个麻烦
killed whatever was after us.
然后  为了保险起见  我们还搬了家
And then -- and then we moved, just to be sure.
迪恩  到底是什么
So what is it, Dean?
是一只怪物  还是一大批怪物
A monster? Or monsters in general?
我不知道
I don't know.
-我只知道可能有危险  -什么危险
- Something might come. - What?
我不知道  它还没来  我无法预料
I don't know. I can't predict what's gonna come after me.
我总得有个数啊
Well, I'm gonna need some parameters.
我们得在这里生活下去
We have to live our lives here.
而且  我要上班  本要上学
I mean, at some point, I have to work. Ben has school.
但是如果你们在我眼皮底下出事...
But if something happens on my watch...
我知道你想要保护我们
I know you're trying to protect us.
但我现在怕的反而是你
But you're kind of scaring me a little, too.
(警告: 该住户受哈珀凯恩保安公司保护监控)
萨姆
Sam?
-你得帮我  就现在  -怎么了
- I need your help. Now. - What's wrong?
-我在跟一个案子  -老弟
- I'm working this job -- - dude.
听着  我只要你帮我这次
Look, I just need you with me on this, okay?
我退出了  彻底退出了
I'm out. I'm staying out.
-破例一次  -为什么
- Make an exception! - For what?
我还有三十分钟到你那
Look, I'm 30 minutes away,
如果你不来见我  我就开到你家去
and I will drive to your door if you don't meet me.
到底什么事儿啊  你居然这样来逼我
And what's so nuts you got to threaten a damn drive-by?
在哪儿
Where is it?
绑在后座上了
Strapped down in the back seat.
欢迎加入《宝贝计划》
Welcome to the party, Guttenberg.
好了
Okay.
弄给我看看
Show me.
我会弄  你之前教过我了
I got it. We've been over this.
-迁就我一次  -装弹
- Humor me. - Load clip.
推滑糟  关保险  开保险
Pull slide. Safety off, safety on.
-还要在窗边和门后撒上盐  -明白
- And salt the windows and the doors. - Of course.
也许我不该去
Maybe I shouldn't go.
没事儿  你想去  去吧
It's okay. You want to go, so go.
-萨姆可以摆平这事的  -迪恩
- You know what? Sam can handle this. - Dean!
别介意  可你要是还不走的话
No offense, but if you don't walk out that door,
我就要开枪撵你了
I'm gonna shoot you.
你现在肯定很怀念前男友吧
Bet you're missing your ex right about now --
很无趣的那家伙
the, uh, boring one.
天哪  闭嘴吧
God, shut up.
小心点  好吗
Just be careful, okay?
拜拜
Bye.
关于这东西  我们知道些什么
All right, so what do we know about this thing?
它速度很快
Well, uh, it was fast.
很怕银器
And it freaked when I cut it with silver.
好  那范围就缩小到了
All right, so that narrows it down to...
食尸鬼啊  僵尸啊
A ghoul, a zombie,
变形怪啊等等等等
a shifter, or about a dozen other things.
资料里好像没说到诱拐婴儿啊
I don't recall seeing babynapping in the profiles.
对  没错
Yeah. Exactly.
你要是知道啥  请随便说
Well, feel free to speak up if you know anything.
安全带
seatbelt.
我又不是小孩子
What am I, in the third grade?
车是用来开的  不是用来装逼的
A car should drive, not be a little bitch.
我没说你啊
Yeah, don't take it personal.
咱得买点装备啊
Well, we need to get some supplies.
车里武器应有尽有
I got an arsenal in the trunk.
不是那些
Not that kind.
好吧  我肯定
All right, I'm pretty sure
这里有面团啊  果冻之类的
that there's some kind of, like, paste or jelly
能涂在小屁屁上的那种
you're supposed to put on their butt.
你看  这种行吗
Like, uh, like that?
行  那个要
Yeah. Grab that.
你怎么懂这些
So how do you know all this?
莉莎有个小侄女
Uh, Lisa's got a baby niece,
我就冒充了几回奶爸
so I've been on a few milk runs.
-哟喂  -给我闭嘴
- Huh. - Shut it.
我不就说个"哟喂"嘛
I just said "Huh."
我说"闭嘴"
I just said "Shut it."
好了  我们得抓紧了
All right, we got to get moving.
这哥们马上就要开闸放水了
We got the waterworks in like t-minus 10, so...
-明白  - 快走
- Yeah. - Okay. Go.
好啊
Hi.
来嘛  坚持住啊哥们  坚持住
Come on, hang in there, buddy. Hang in there, man.
迪恩  哄他别哭了
Dean, make it stop.
怎么哄
How?
大家都看着  跟咱俩虐待儿童似的
Everyone's staring at us like we're child abusers.
喂奶
Feed it.
喂过了
We fed it!
那要怎样
Then what?
我哪儿知道  我又听不懂他说话
I don't know. You think I speak baby?
是不是该换尿布了
Maybe he needs a diaper change.
天呐  希望不是
Oh, god, I hope not.
怎么啦
What's the matter?
他叫什么
What's his name?
-约翰  -鲍比
- John. - Bobby.
鲍比·约翰
Bobby John.
你好呀  鲍比·约翰
Hi, Bobby John.
真是个小帅哥啊
Aren't you handsome?
抱抱行吗
May I?
哦  这个...
Oh. Uh...
我知道了  鲍比·约翰尿裤裤了呢
I see now. Bobby John's a little wet.
没别的意思  不过你俩看起来真憔悴
No offense -- you two look exhausted.
我不介意的
I-I don't mind.
天知道我换了几百万片尿布
Lord knows I've changed a million diapers.
那真是...
That's...
您人真是太好了  谢谢
That's -- that's a really nice offer. Thank you.
不过我想我们应付得来
But, uh I think we've got it.
没关系的  我很乐意帮忙
Oh, it's nothing. Happy to help.
把孩子给我  别逼我一刀扎在你脖子上
Give me the baby before I stab you in your neck.
迪恩
Dean!
救命啊
Help me!
他要杀人啦
Hey! He's hurting me!
放开她
Get off of her!
好  我放开
Okay. All right.
别激动
All right.
快开  快...
Go go go...
那个变形怪要这孩子干嘛
What the hell's a shifter want with a baby, anyway?
鬼知道
You tell me.
再说它又是怎么找到咱俩的
And how the hell did it find us?
天呐  这玩意儿谁设计的  宇航局吗
God, who the designed this thing, NASA?
你知道  从我离开这孩子家开始
You know, it could have been following me this whole time
-他可能就一直跟着我  -不说那个了
- Since the baby's house. - All right, you know what?
咱得赶紧找个下脚处
We got to get off the road,
给鲍比·约翰找个安全的地方栖身
get, uh, Bobby John here someplace safe,
再想对策
figure this thing out.
好了  好了  宝宝不哭
Okay, all right. Shh! Shh! Easy, kid.
(禁止入内)
监控台86号  请讲
Control, 86. Go ahead.
我需要查一辆伊利诺斯车的行踪
I need a 10-28 on Illinois plates --
车牌号是"I4ZO892"
"I" As in India, 4, zulu, oscar, 8, 9, 2.
好了  你看这样行不行
Okay. All right. You know what?
我花钱雇你躺着别动
I'll pay you money if you sit still.
这根本就是拆除便便炸弹
This is like defusing an I.E.D. With poop.
好了  行啦  换完啦
Okay. All right, all right.
好啦  你是宝贝鲍比·约翰
All right. You are golden, Bobby John.
该睡觉觉咯
Time to hit the hay.
迪恩  你那样还得把他招哭
Dean, you're just gonna make it cranky again.
别说话  管用了
Shh! It's working.
好咯  我要把你放下去
Okay, if I put you down,
你要像个男子汉一样哦
you gonna be a man about it?
咋了
What?
你刚真是
Y-you're just, uh,
说实话...真是不赖啊
actually... Not awful at that.
哥们  在我手里他还能活着是他命大
Dude, I'm barely keeping that thing alive.
不  不是  说真的
No, no, no, seriously.
简直就是超级奶爸附身啊
You got a whole Dr. Huxtable vibe coming off of you.
你可真是...当爹的料
You're like... Father material.
是啊  最近确实当爹了
Yeah, well, I kind of had to be lately, you know?
硬着头皮上呗  你说对吧
Sink or swim, right?
你是说本
You mean Ben.
是啊  我是说本
Yeah, I mean Ben.
我是说  我知道他不是我亲生的
I mean, I know he's not my kid,
但  我也不清楚  我好像开始
But -- I don't know, I'm starting to feel like...
把他当亲生的了
Yeah, he is.
每次想到咱们是怎么长大的
When I think about the way we grew up...
我觉得我有机会
I don't know. I kind of feel like I have a chance
能让本的好过一点  你明白吗
to do something different with Ben, you know?
你确定吗
You sure about that?
你什么意思
What do you mean?
你看...
Look...
你显然在意那孩子
You clearly care about the kid.
但是呢
But?
但是  让他们四处漂泊  闭门不出
But...Moving them around, keeping them on lockdown...
你确实让他们闭门不出  对吧
I mean, you do have them on lockdown, right?
这和你我成长的环境有什么区别
How is any of that different from how we were raised?
所以你的意思是...
So you're saying...
我不想让任何人卷入这种生活
I'm not shoving anybody into this life, okay?
这是一时的
This is temporary.
还记得老爸总说那是一时的吗
Dad always said it was temporary, Dean.
"一时"持续了22年
He said it for 22 years.
我懂你的初衷
Look, I get it.
你想要保护他们  这再好不过
You want to watch out for them. That's great.
我只是想问你...
I'm just asking --
你要怎么做  才不会像爸爸那样
How do you do that and not turn into dad?
糟糕  我怎么会漏掉这个
Crap. I can't believe I missed this.
怎么了
What?
榆树街上的房子
This house on Elm --
母亲被杀  婴儿被抢
the -- the mother was killed, baby was grabbed,
但那时父亲不在房子里
but daddy wasn't living in the house at the time,
所以他还活着
so he's still alive.
我们去找他谈谈如何
What do you say we go and have a chat?
走吧
I say let's.
你去吧
You go.
你确定吗
You sure?
除非你能给鲍比·约翰找个警徽
Unless you got a badge for Bobby John,
不然我必须留下
yeah, I'm sure.
味道不错  是吧
It's good, isn't it?
我
I just...
我还是不敢相信
I still can't believe it.
我是说  要是死了也就算了
I mean, i-it's one thing to die like...that.
可怜的婴儿
Poor baby.
消失得无影无踪
Just into thin air.
你们还真是没用啊
No thanks to you guys.
这也是我来这里的原因
Well, that's why I'm here.
你们申请离婚了是吗
You had filed for divorce?
不好意思  这很重要
It's important. I'm sorry.
她
She, uh...
她在外面偷情
she cheated on me.
被我抓到了
And, well, I caught her.
那你知道对方是谁吗
And did you know the other man?
不知道  我没有抓到现行
No, I-I mean, I didn't catch her catch her,
但她骗了我
but...she lied to me.
好的
Okay.
我们很久没有做...
We hadn't...
...你知道的
...you know, in a while,
然后  她突然就怀孕了
and -- and then -- then she's pregnant.
-她怎么说  -她说孩子是我的
- What did she say?  - She said it was mine.
我知道
I know.
我说  "这不可能"
And -- and I said, "That's impossible,"
我不相信她说的
and "What is she talking about?"
她说"难道你不记得你出城那次
And she says, "Don't you remember when you went out of town
提早回来了  然后我们就..."
and you came back early and we..."
但你没有
But you didn't?
是的
No.
我在参加垒球锦标赛
I was at a damn softball tournament.
无论那是谁  他才是孩子的父亲
Whoever he was, he's the father.
什么事
Yeah?
我和父亲谈过了
I talked to the father.
他没问题  但是那婴儿
He checks out. But the baby...
怎么了
Yeah?
我想它父亲是变形怪
I think the shapeshifter is its dad.
是嘛
You think?
我是管理员  里面没事吧
Manager. Everything okay in there?
没事  我们  我们很好
Yeah. No, we're -- we're -- we're fine,
谢谢  晚安
thank you. Good night.
我接到一些投诉  能开下门吗  先生
There's been complaints. You mind opening the door, sir?
现在不方便
Uh, it's not a good time.
我们刚洗完澡
Just -- just got out of the shower.
-别挡道  -我不会让你得逞的
- Get out of the way.  - Yeah, that's not gonna happen.
婴儿应该和他父亲在一起
A child should be with his father.
实话说
Well, I got to be honest --
我觉得你们俩没丁点相象
I'm not really seeing the family resemblance.
没说我是他父亲
I'm not just talking about me.
我说的是我们的父亲
I'm talking about our father.
押金拿不回来了
Well, there goes our deposit.
知道吗  这招还真妙
You know, it's pretty smart, actually.
变形怪假扮成在保安公司工作的警卫
I mean, shifter poses as a guard for the security company
以便接近那房子
to get near the house.
然后研究这个家庭
Then it scopes out the fam.
没错  爸爸出门  变形怪就来冒充他
Yeah. Then daddy takes off, and the shifter becomes daddy.
喝几杯酒  跟妈妈嘿咻一下
Few glasses of wine, shakes mama's trees,
九个月后回来带走它的成果
comes back in nine months to collect its prize.
我都不知道它们还能生娃娃
I didn't even know they had babies.
我以为它们只不过是天生的怪物
I thought they were just freaks of nature,
跟X战警一样
like -- like X-men style.
是啊  所谓活到老学到老是吧
Yeah, you learn something new every day, huh?
我还没见过怪物婴儿呢
I've never seen a baby monster before.
是啊
Yeah.
话说回来  它还不是怪物
Of course, it's not really a monster.
还只是个婴儿
I mean, it's still just a baby.
这不是它的错  谁让它爹是变形怪呢
It's not its fault its dad's a shifter.
是没错  但它还是个变形怪
Right. But it's a shifter, too.
这也改变不了我们要
It still doesn't change the fact that we've got to --
我们要照顾它的事实
we've got to look after this thing.
但我们要拿它怎么办
But what the hell are we gonna do with it?
我们又不能把它扔给孤儿院
We can't actually drop it off at an orphanage.
要是它变成亚洲人会引起恐慌
They might get upset when it turns asian.
找萨穆埃尔
Samuel.
什么
What?
找萨穆埃尔
Samuel.
他知道该怎么做
He'll know what to do.
你要把它带给一群猎魔人
You want to bring it to a bunch of hunters?
他们不只是猎魔人  迪恩  他们是家人
They're not just hunters, Dean. They're our family.
-我们不了解他们  - 我了解
- We don't know them.  - I do.
不是每个猎人都神经兮兮
Not every hunter is a head case.
我说  萨穆埃尔跟你就很像
I mean, Samuel is actually a lot like you.
我就是个神经兮兮的猎魔人
I'm a freakin' head case.
那  你出个更好的主意
Well...pitch a better idea, then.
很好  我们这就去找萨穆埃尔
Great. Samuel it is.
还有谁比你伪装得更好呢
Well, aren't you just the best disguise
小怪物
a monster ever wore.
不就开个玩笑嘛  迪恩
I'm kidding, Dean.
别紧张
Relax.
你也有话要说吗
Oh, you got something to say?
没有  好  那你就站那里打量我吧
No? All right. Well, you just stand there and think at me.
我们下一步怎么做
So, what's our next move?
我倒有几个主意
Well, I got a couple ideas.
迪恩  给我抱抱
Dean, let me see the little guy.
没事  我抱着就行了
That's all right. I got him.
你以为我想干什么
What do you think I'm gonna do?
你不会想听的
You really don't want me to answer that question.
我很好奇
Well, I'm curious.
你到底觉得我们是谁
Who exactly do you think we are?
猎魔人
Hunters.
真有意思
That's funny.
我还以为是自家人
Here I've been thinking we're family.
都不要吵了
Hey. Let's not get worked up.
不吵就不吵
Yeah, yeah. Let's not.
给我吧  迪恩
Here, Dean.
没事
It's fine.
给我来抱
Let me take him.
没关系
It's okay.
小可爱
Hey, there.
个头可真不小
Oh, you're a big fella, aren't you?
很久没抱过这样的小家伙了
Yeah. I haven't held one of these in a long time.
你妈那会可瘦了
Your mom was the tiniest.
小脑袋上光秃秃的
She was bald as a cue ball.
那我们该怎么处理他
All right, so what the hell are we gonna do with him?
养大他
Raise him.
Raise him?
-你有什么其他建议吗  -但是
- What, you got another suggestion? - But...
把他丢在外面太危险了  迪恩
It's dangerous out there for him, Dean.
那在这里呢
And what about in here?
我们难道要解刨研究他么
What, are we gonna study him, poke at him?
你思想太扭曲了  迪恩
Your mind goes right to torture, Dean.
别以为大家都跟你一样
Don't assume that for everyone.
你到底想说什么
What exactly are you trying to say?
抱歉  听说你在下面折磨人
Sorry, I heard about what you majored in,
折磨得太久了
down in the pit?
你不爽个毛啊
What the hell is your problem, man?
我越看你越不顺眼了
You're starting to become a pain in my ass.
克里斯蒂安  给个面子  他是我哥
Christian, take it easy, man. He's my brother.
都唧唧歪歪完没
We all done bristling up here or what?
没人会把他怎么样  迪恩
Nobody's doing anything to him, Dean.
等他长大  我们就告诉他真相
When he's old enough, we throw it to him.
他要愿意帮助我们  那最好
He wants to volunteer to help out, that's fine.
一定会很棒的
Could be great.
棒什么
How?
想想他会成为什么样的猎魔人
Think of the kind of hunter he'll grow up to be.
你们都搞笑吧
You all are joking, right?
拜托
I mean, come on!
你们不能就这么领养个变形怪
You can't... Angelina Jolie a shapeshifter.
把孩子给我
Give me the baby.
你怎么就不肯相信我呢  迪恩
Why can't you give me an inch of trust, Dean?
也许因为你们俩突然死而复生
Maybe because you two are suddenly back from the dead,
而只有我一个人
and I seem to be the only one
对整件事十分好奇
who wants to know how the hell that happened!
不光你想知道是怎么回事
You're not the only one who wants to know.
你们这些所谓家人太神秘了
There's just a little too much mystery with this family
让我很不爽
for me to get comfy.
那就别管了  别总针对我们
Then don't. But don't put it on us.
我们只想让你融入这里
All we're trying to do is invite you in.
-克里斯蒂安  -在
- Christian. - Yeah?
你和艾琳还是怀不上孩子吗
You and Arlene, still no luck on the baby front?
没错
Not yet, no.
那你们还想要孩子吗
But you want one?
当然想
Yeah, we do.
-等等  -放心  迪恩
- Wait, hold on. - It's okay, Dean.
没事的
It's all right.
恭喜你们
Congrats.
是个男孩  算是吧
It's a boy...Sometimes.
我家终于有后了
The crap I do for this family.
你们不是来真的吧
You're kidding, right?
哪凉快哪待着去  迪恩
Go to hell, Dean.
你根本就不可能抚养一个孩子
Well, you have no business raising anything.
为什么  迪恩
Why, Dean?
就因为他是猎魔人吗
Because he's a hunter?
检查后门
Check the back door.
你们去楼下避难室  那里很安全
Downstairs -- panic room. He'll be safe there.
走
Go.
这里有我们  快去
We got it! Go! Now!
你们抢了我们的"人"
You have something of ours.
我知道他在这
I know he's here.
能感觉出来
I can feel him.
快跑
Run!
-马克  -不要
- Mark! - No!
放松  大个子
Easy, tiger.
去拿银网
Get the silver nets.
把他绑起来
We're gonna box him up.
别哭了  鲍比·约翰
Come on, Bobby John.
给我安静点
You have got to keep quiet.
听上去他们不太妙啊
That does not sound good up there.
好吧  我上去看看
All right. I'm going up.
你俩老实待在这
Stay with the baby.
我去...
What the...
-把孩子给我  -没门儿
- Give me the baby. - No way in hell.
现在看来肯定确有其事了
Pretty sure it's not a myth now.
是啊
Yeah.
那到底是什么怪物
What the hell was that thing?
-我们认为可能是始祖  -什么始祖
- We think it may have been an Alpha. - An Alpha? Like...
每个怪物总有一个祖先
Like all monsters come from somewhere, right?
你们觉得这个是
And you think that this one was the...
变形怪始祖
King Shapeshifter.
生育其他后代的第一代变形怪
The first one who spawned all the others.
这里面学问可多着呢
There's tons of lore about it.
是始祖
The first one?
所以它有如此强大的能力
That's why it was so strong.
也是我们无法阻止它的原因
And why nothing we had stopped it.
他说过这婴儿在哪儿他都能找到
And he said that he could find the baby anywhere,
它能感觉到  它们之间有灵犀
that he could feel it, like there's a connection.
传说中也有提到
That's in the lore, too.
那它究竟为什么要这个婴儿呢
What the hell's it want with babies, anyway?
组个垒球队吧
Softball team?
我也不知道
I got no clue.
好吧
Great.
那  我们怎么干掉它
Well, then, how do we kill it?
我不知道能否干掉它
I don't know if we can.
真有趣
You know, it's funny.
什么有趣
What's that?
你在旅馆把那变形怪干掉之前
Just before you, uh, ganked that shifter in the motel,
它提到了父亲
he mentioned a father,
现在看来说得通了  原来它是说始祖
Which makes sense now 'cause he meant the Alpha.
是啊  我也觉得是
Huh. Yeah, I guess so.
你听到它说的话了吗
Did you hear him say that?
不知道
I don't know.
情况紧急  没注意
Kind of a hot moment, you know?
怎么了
Why?
因为如果你听到了
Well, 'cause if you heard him,
那你就知道这个始祖的存在
then -- then you knew the Alpha was out there.
是啊
Okay.
如果你知道始祖存在
And if you knew the Alpha was out there,
那你就知道它会寻找这婴儿
then you knew he might come after the baby.
这样的话  你就可以用孩子做诱饵
In which case, you were using the baby as bait.
你就是这么计划的吧
So, was that the plan?
-利用婴儿做诱饵  -当然不是了
- To use the baby as bait?  - Of course not.
迪恩  我只是觉得萨穆埃尔那儿最安全
Dean, I just thought Samuel's was the safest place.
就这样
That's all.
是啊  当然
Right. Of course.
不  我没抓到它
No, I didn't catch it.
它杀了我们三个人
It killed three of my people.
我用麻醉大象的麻醉枪射它  根本不管用
I shot it full of elephant tranquilizer, and it chuckled!
老实讲  我不确定是否想找到它
To be honest, I'm not sure I want to find it.
但我们会找到方法把它抓住的
But, yeah, we will find a way to catch it.
好  行  我会把它包装好
Yeah, sure. I'll bring it right to you --
作为礼品带给你
gift-wrapped.
本在哪儿
Hey. Where's Ben?
在骑车
Bike ride.
怎么了
What?
我不知道要怎么办  莉莎
I don't -- I don't know what to do here, Lis.
如果我知道怎样才能让你们最安全
I mean, if I knew for sure what the safest thing was,
我会去做的
Then I'd do it --
留在这里  保护你们
stay here and look after you guys...
还是走得越远越好  但是...
Or get as far away as I possibly can, but...
我不知道
I don't know.
我知道我最近某些行为
And I get what I've been doing lately, you know,
大声呵斥什么的  还有
with the yelling and the...
像个狱警一样
acting like a...
把你们当犯人看着
like a prison guard.
这不是  不是我
It's just -- that's not me.
我告诫自己不能成为这样的人
You tell yourself you're not gonna be something, you know?
我爸爸曾经的行为就是如此
You know, my dad was exactly like this,
一直都这样
All the time.
-我真的很怕和他一样  -迪恩
- And it scared the hell out of me. - Dean.
我能说句实话吗
Can I be honest?
你在这儿我们或许会更安全
Maybe we're safer with you here.
也可能是你离开更安全
Maybe gone.
我也不清楚
I don't know.
我确信的一点是
The one thing that I do know
你不是个建筑工人
is that you're not a construction worker.
你是一个猎魔人
You're a hunter.
现在你弟弟出现了
And now you know your brother's out there.
事情就变得不一样了
Things are different.
-你不想呆在这儿了  -不  我想的
- You don't want to be here, Dean. - Yes, I do.
好吧
Okay.
好吧  但  但你也想跟你弟弟一起
Okay, but -- but you also want to be there, and...
我理解
I get it.
你这么活着会很痛苦
You're white-knuckling it, living like this,
好像你真的是什么凶神恶煞一样
Like what you really are is some bad, awful thing,
但是  你不是
But... You're not.
我不会在每次你临行前
But I'm not gonna have this discussion
都说这些
every time you leave.
因为你...
And this is --
你会不断离开  所以我只说这一次
This is just gonna keep happening, so...
我要你离开
I need you to go.
我不能丢下你和本不管
I-I can't just lose you and Ben.
-我不是这个意思  -你说让我走
- That's not what I'm saying. - You're saying hit the road.
迪恩  如果规定
Dean, if there's some rule
这必须要有所取舍
that says this all has to be either-or...
我们破了这规定如何
How 'bout we break it?
我和本会在这儿
Me and Ben will be here, and...
你能来的时候就过来
You come when you can.
只是
Just...
答应我完好无损地回来  行吗
Just come in one piece, okay?
你真觉得我们这样做合适吗  有用吗
And you really think we could pull something like that off?
值得一试  不是吗
It's worth a shot, right?